<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>trading on deskriders</title>
    <link>/tags/trading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in trading on deskriders</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:10:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/trading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Short Straddles with Laddering</title>
      <link>/posts/1736507408-short-straddle-with-laddering/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 11:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/1736507408-short-straddle-with-laddering/</guid>
      <description>Short Straddles
For e.g. Given that our account can trade 5 SPX contracts at once.
We can either trade 1 contract every day - 5 different positions Or we can trade all 5 contracts at the same time in a single trade - 1 position Or we can stagger 5 contracts in a single trade. Add 1 contract every day Here are the results
(a) 1 Contract Every Day (Max 5 Positions) &amp;gt; 45 DTE Expiry</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short Straddles with RSI based market filters</title>
      <link>/posts/1736250948-short-straddle-rsi-market-filter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 11:55:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/1736250948-short-straddle-rsi-market-filter/</guid>
      <description>Hypothesis: What if we avoid new trade if RSI is overbought or oversold?
Backtest with different RSI thresholds and different RSI periods
RSI Thresholds:
RSI Period: 4 rsi_low_values=(0 10 20 30) rsi_high_values=(70 80 90 100) Best Parameters by Expectancy Ratio:
rsi_low_threshold=20, rsi_high_threshold=100
Expectancy Ratio: 1.08
This combination shows the highest expectancy ratio, indicating it provides the best risk-adjusted returns. rsi_low_threshold=30, rsi_high_threshold=100
Expectancy Ratio: 1.06
Second-best expectancy ratio. rsi_low_threshold=30, rsi_high_threshold=70
Expectancy Ratio: 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key Metrics for Evaluating Trading System Performance</title>
      <link>/posts/1734292310-key-metrics-trading-system-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 19:51:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/1734292310-key-metrics-trading-system-performance/</guid>
      <description>Summary from this tweet from Laurens Bensdorp
Here&amp;rsquo;s what seems to matter most:
Core Performance Metrics: CAGR (Compound Annual Growth Rate) and its variants CAGR/UI (Ulcer Index) ratio CAGR/MaxDD (Maximum Drawdown) Some use RAR (Risk-Adjusted Return) instead of CAGR for more date-independent analysis Risk Management Metrics: Maximum Drawdown Average Exposure (particularly important for mean reversion strategies) Drawdown Correlation Total Drawdown Ulcer Index Trade Quality Indicators: Profit Factor Expectancy System Quality Number (SQN) Win Ratio Standard Deviation of Returns Coefficient of Variation Strategy-Specific Considerations: For Stocks: Individual trade statistics Capital utilization efficiency Average capital use per trade For Futures: Risk metrics Drawdown analysis Trend gain patterns Advanced Analysis: Walk-forward testing results consistency Performance during &amp;ldquo;black swan&amp;rdquo; events (1987 crash, flash crashes) Stagnation periods Monthly Return on Risk (RoR) Monthly dollar performance Evaluation Method Tip: Some traders use conditional formatting with color ranking to aggregate multiple metrics, helping identify top-performing systems more easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysing a very simple Short Straddle strategy</title>
      <link>/posts/1734004071-options-analysis-pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 11:47:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/1734004071-options-analysis-pipeline/</guid>
      <description>Gather data The Options data is retrieved from optionsdx. This page documents the field definitions
The downloaded files will be zipped, so extract them into a single directory. It&amp;rsquo;ll look something like this:
Import data Use the optionsdx-data-importer.py script to import all the data in an SQLite database
$ uvr optionsdx-data-importer.py --input $(pwd)/data/spy_eod --output data/spy_eod.db -v The finished database will have an options_data table with all the data from the downloaded files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to make/lose money with buying dips</title>
      <link>/posts/1719050638-rsi-dips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 11:03:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/1719050638-rsi-dips/</guid>
      <description>Overview: Analyzes stock data for RSI dips below a specified lower threshold and subsequent rises above a higher threshold. Simulates buy and sell actions based on these RSI movements Calculates potential profits/losses from these simulated trades Provides a summary of dips and performance metrics Source [GitHub] https://github.com/namuan/trading-utils/blob/main/rsi_dips.py
See the top of the script on how to run it</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Stocks in Google Sheet</title>
      <link>/posts/1714824523-track-stocks-csv-google-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 13:08:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/1714824523-track-stocks-csv-google-sheet/</guid>
      <description>Generate CSV reports $ ./generate-csv-reports.sh 2&amp;gt;&amp;amp;1 | grep &amp;#34;Exporting report&amp;#34; Combine all reports $ python3 combine-all-csvs.py Paste into Google Sheet Re-arrange and apply formulas Last Close: =GOOGLEFINANCE(C3,&amp;#34;price&amp;#34;) Current Code: =G3*E3 TV Link: =HYPERLINK(CONCATENATE(&amp;#34;https://www.tradingview.com/chart/?symbol=&amp;#34;, C3), C3) Chart: =sparkline(googlefinance(C3,&amp;#34;price&amp;#34;,today()-30,today())) Profit Loss: =I3-H3 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What happened next when SPY jumped over 2%</title>
      <link>/posts/1708762767-spy-pct-move/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 08:19:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/1708762767-spy-pct-move/</guid>
      <description>Last week, SPY jump over 2% on Thursday
This was surprising for many as the market is already up a lot.
So, I wanted to see what happened the next day when SPY jumped over 2%.
Here are the results over the last 10 years.
The next day change after a 2% jump
Next Day Change Number of Occurrences &amp;lt; 0 36 &amp;gt; 0 25 &amp;gt; 1 % 13 &amp;gt; 2 % 3 &amp;gt; 3 % 1 This doesn&amp;rsquo;t tell us much, but it does give us a good indication of what is going on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
