<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>productivity on deskriders</title>
    <link>/tags/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in productivity on deskriders</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 16:38:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tooltip # 1 :: Creating command line launcher for IntelliJ products</title>
      <link>/posts/013-tooltip-1-creating-intellij-launcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 16:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/013-tooltip-1-creating-intellij-launcher/</guid>
      <description>This is hopefully first of many (tool)tips where I create a very short ( ~ 30sec -&amp;gt; 1min) video 📹covering a specific task.
In this first video, we&#39;ll look at creating a command line launcher for IntelliJ. Although this is created using IntelliJ IDEA but the same option should be available in WebStorm, PhpStorm, PyCharm etc.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Simple setup to remember one-liners/code snippets</title>
      <link>/posts/012-keeping-snippets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 10:13:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/012-keeping-snippets/</guid>
      <description>Here is a simple setup explaining a comment I made on Reddit.
All I have is a notes.txt under my home directory where the snippets (one-liners) are stored in the following format. Note that I don&#39;t store block of code or longer text here as they&#39;ll become difficult to search.
find . -type f -name &amp;#39;*.txt&amp;#39; -exec sed -i &amp;#39;&amp;#39; s/this/that/g {} + # search and replace sed find It starts with the command then # and a brief comment on what it does.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing DevRider :: One Desktop App for Common Development Tools</title>
      <link>/posts/010-introducing-devrider/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 19:05:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/010-introducing-devrider/</guid>
      <description>There is a serious problem with the state of simple development tools on the internet.
Most of the websites providing simple encoders/decoders/formatters/prettifiers are filled with ads and popups which makes it annoying and risky to use.
And then there is also a huge problem with privacy and leaking any private data that is used on any of these websites.
Although it is impossible to replace them altogether, let me introduce you to DevRider, a new open source to provide some of the common tools in an extensible desktop application.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>